本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  阿好
・ 翻译  麦结
■
・ 翻译  敏基
・ 翻译  惠子
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  茶炒栗子
・ 翻译  艾瑞卡
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  幸田实果子
译  somehacker
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
阿包  Sagelibra  兜兜兜爹  Kallen  阿包  Sagelibra  兜兜兜爹  Kallen  阿包  Sagelibra  兜兜兜爹  Kallen  阿包  Sagelibra  兜兜兜爹  Kallen
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季 第十三集
西风航空公司提醒
航程变动
飞往伊斯坦布尔的763航班
请与39号登机口的工作人员联系
请注意
Your attention, please.
飞往伊斯坦布尔的763航班超售
Flight 763 to Istanbul has been oversold.
目前尚未分配到座位的乘客
Passengers who do not yet have a seat assignment
请与39号登机口的工作人员联系
should check with the agent at gate 39.
非常抱歉  威利先生  您无法乘坐本航班了
I'm so sorry, Mr. Wiley, we've had to bump you.
我可以安排您
I can get you on the next
搭乘明早直飞伊斯坦布尔的航班
nonstop to Istanbul tomorrow morning.
不过好像服务器出了问题
But I'm told there's a problem with the server.
错误
无法连接服务器
您托运了几件行李
How many bags did you check?
没有行李
No baggage.
错误
无法连接服务器
远程连接已建立
发现备用服务器路径
好了
Here we go.
好像启用备用系统了
It looks like the system is back up.
我看到您之前的预定
I see your previous reservation
是一张单程票
was for a one-way ticket.
您现在要订返程票吗
Would you like to purchase the return leg now?
我不确定几时回来
I'm not sure when I'll be back.
您太幸运了
You're in luck.
有一个航班上还有座位
A seat just opened up on a flight
经停罗马
with a stopover in Rome.
还是头等舱呢
And it's first-class.
要了
Done.
33号登机口  座位1D  祝您搭乘愉快
Gate 33, seat 1D. Enjoy your flight.
谢谢
Thank you.
威利先生  有对新婚夫妇正在度蜜月
Mr. Wiley, we have some newlyweds on their honeymoon
他们非常希望能坐在一起
who would really love to sit together.
您介意换个座位吗
Would you mind changing seats?
没问题  霍莉
Sure, Holly.
我带您去新座位
I'll show you to your new seat.
这里
Right here.
我是头等舱空乘
I'll be the attendant in first class.
需要我为您拿点什么吗  来点喝的
Is there anything I can get for you right now? Something to drink?
不  没事  谢了
No, I'm fine, thanks.
不
No.
不  我告诉杰里走开
No, I told Jerry to walk away.
是啊  有时候就得
Yeah, well, sometimes you gotta
把钱撂在桌子上
leave the money on the table.
叫他们知道哥不在乎
You make 'em think you don't need it.
多绅士啊  谢谢
Such a gentlemen, thank you.
那可是我的[奢侈品牌]"途明"包
That's my Tumi that you're sliding over.
别给碰坏了
Try not to smash it.
过去  乘飞机都要盛装的
Used to be, people dressed up to fly.
绅士们要衣装笔挺
Gentlemen required to wear a jacket and tie.
倒不是说男人都要穿西装  但是
Not that a man needs to wear a suit, but--
霍莉
Holly?
改主意了  还是来杯冰威士忌吧
On second thought, Scotch Rocks would be great.
没问题
No problem.
不用担心
Don't worry about that.
杰里当然会听我的
Of course Jerry is gonna listen to me.
杰里总是听我的
Because Jerry always listens to me.
联调局今天大获全胜
A victory for the FBI today
他们粉碎了特大网上毒品市场
as they busted a major online drug market.
联调局粉碎网络毒品集市
先生  前舱门已经关闭了
Sir, the forward door has been closed.
您得把手机关掉
You'll need to turn off your phone.
等下
One sec.
我说甜心
Listen, sweetheart,
你要是看过科学杂志
if you ever bothered to pick up a scientific journal,
就应该知道所谓的电子干扰
you'd know that all this electronic interference stuff
不过是扯蛋的
is really just a bunch of B.S.
你不如就回去
So why don't you hop yourself back up there
告诉他们可以起飞
and tell 'em that we can go,
让我打我的电话得了
while I take my call?
好吧
Okay.
抱歉  弗兰克  一笨空姐儿
Sorry, Frank, some idiot stewardess.
能帮把手吗  卡洛斯
Mind giving me a hand here, Carlos?
抱歉  经济舱这儿忙着呢
Sorry, got my hands full with coach.
是你想做头等舱的  记得吗
You wanted first, remember?
打扰下  先生
Excuse me, sir?
看来他说睡着了
Looks like he talked himself out.
不过他可能需要条毯子
Bet he could use a blanket.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们的飞行高度已达三千米
We have reached 10,000 feet.
现在可以随意使用
It is now safe to use
所有经许可的电子设备
all approved electronic devices.
去下洗手间
Gotta hit the head.
您有什么需要吗  威利先生
Did you need something, Mr. Wiley?
只是活动下腿
Just stretching my legs.
盥洗室
使用中
里边半天不出来了
Guy's been in there a while.
不如试试后边那间
Might wanna try the one in back.
网络来电
喂
Yes?
芬奇
Finch?
里瑟先生  你在哪里
Mr. Reese, where are you?
为什么用网络电话
And why are you calling over V.o.I.P.?
你说呢
You tell me.
你把我安排到了这儿
You're the one who put me here.
我们不能再这样继续下去了  芬奇
We can't keep doing this, Finch.
安排到哪儿  继续什么
Put you where? Doing what?
让我的航班超售  改我的座位
Overbooking my flight, changing my seat.
你在飞机上
Are you on a plane?
还有两名联邦法警和被护送人员
With two Federal Marshals and their transport.
我告诉过你  不要任务  不要号码
I told you: no more missions, no more numbers.
虽然我不同意你离开
While I don't agree with your decision to leave,
但我会尊重
I certainly respect it.
我没给你安排任务  里瑟先生
I did not send you on a mission, Mr. Reese.
那谁安排我到这趟航班的
Then who put me on this flight?
预计到达时间  8小时20分钟
■
监控关键执行人
预计到达时间
重大灾难事件
生成预测
自发解决
关键执行人激活
死亡：马修斯  欧文
重大灾难事件
生成预测
自发解决
死亡：关键执行人
化名：里瑟  约翰
特工干预
关键执行人激活
死亡：马修斯  欧文
死亡：关键执行人
化名：里瑟  约翰
重大灾难事件
生成预测
自发解决
关键执行人新任务指派
法警不省人事  枪还丢了
An incapacitated Marshal with a missing weapon.
这可肯定不妙  里瑟先生
That definitely does not look good, Mr. Reese.
也肯定不是巧合
It definitely doesn't look like a coincidence either.
你是说你没有收到号码
You're telling me you didn't get a number?
没有  相信我对你说的话  里瑟先生
I didn't. Believe me when I tell you, Mr. Reese,
我没有安排你陷入这种境地
I did not put you in your current predicament.
那我为什么会在这架飞机上
Why else would I be on this plane?
我斗胆猜一下
I can only hazard a guess.
你在那里是机器安排的
You're there because the machine put you there.
看来你的机器没收到我的辞呈啊  哈罗德
I guess your machine didn't get my letter of resignation, Harold.
替我捎个信儿  行吗
Give it a message for me, will ya?
我辞职
I quit.
收到了  里瑟先生
Message received, Mr. Reese.
但你准备怎么处理
But what do you plan to do about
盥洗室里那位不省人事的法警
the unconscious marshal in the lavatory?
与我无关
That's not my problem.
载满平民的飞机上丢了把枪就肯定有关
A loose firearm in a plane full of civilians most certainly is.
你说过有两名法警
You said there were two Marshals.
另一位呢
Where's the second?
盯着被护送人员呢
Keeping an eye on their transport.
那人坐在4C
Guy's sitting in 4C,
就是机器发给我的信息
the same seat the machine sent me.
看来飞机上还有同谋
It appears there may be an accessory on that flight,
手里还有把枪
one who is now armed.
你应该没带枪吧
I don't suppose you are too?
就算带了  我也不会
Even if I were, I wouldn't risk
在民航客机上开枪
firing a weapon on a commercial flight.
子弹一碰到玻璃
Bullet hits a window,
飞机会瞬间失压
plane will depressurize in seconds.
那你计划如何控制局势
So how do you plan to control the situation?
没计划
I don't.
因为我不接受这任务
Because I'm not accepting the mission.
我去告诉法警他搭档出了事
I'll tell the Marshal what happened to his coworker.
然后就是他的问题  与我无关了
Whatever happens next is his problem, not mine.
-让开啦  哥们  -提图斯  过来
- Move it, buddy. - Titus, come here.
我不知道你们护送的这人是谁
I don't know who this guy is you're transporting,
犯了什么事
or what he's done--
"据称"犯了什么事
What I've allegedly done.
先生  我必须要求你
Sir, I'm gonna have to ask you
避免跟他有任何交流
to refrain from engaging with this man.
抱歉  是他跟我交流
I'm sorry. He engaged with me.
不  我是纠正你  两者完全不同
No, I corrected you. There's a difference.
你的搭档昏迷在前舱盥洗室
Your partner's out cold in the forward latrine,
他的枪丢了
and his weapon's missing.
可能有人想帮这位被护送人员逃跑
Someone may be trying to help your transport here escape.
怎么扯出阴谋论了
What's with the conspiracy theories,
暗黑狂暴先生
Mr. Dark and stormy?
我可不想逃跑
I am not trying to escape.
好吧  我再喜欢呼吸这里头
Okay, as much as I love sucking in this
封闭的满是耐药金葡菌的空气
recirculated M.R.S.A. air,
-也不会  -闭嘴
- there is nothing I-- - Quiet.
我不知道你是谁
Look, I don't know who you are,
想搞什么鬼
or if you're trying to pull something.
但我知道这不关你的事
But I know this isn't your business.
麻烦你滚回到自己的座位
I need you to get your ass up and return to your seat,
马上
immediately.
你说得对
You're right.
这不关我的事
This isn't any of my business.
祝你愉快  法警
Have a nice day, Marshal.
有你的信儿  混蛋
Got a message for you, canalla.
拉斐尔向你问好
Raphael sends his regards.
他扎我
He just stabbed me.
他是不是
Is he--
被下药了
Drugged.
死不了  给
He'll live. Here.
哥伦比亚共和国
枪骑兵
Lanceros.
这边没事吧
Everything all right here?
肯定是把抗焦虑药兑酒喝了
Must've mixed his anxiety meds with his booze.
可能脱水了
Probably dehydrated.
睡一觉就好了
He'll sleep it off.
法警也脱水了吗
And the Marshal is dehydrated too?
有的人很难在红眼航班上保持不睡
Hard for some people to stay awake on a red-eye.
真希望我也有这种问题
Wish I had that problem.
-还有毯子吗  -有
- Do you have any more blankets? - Sure.
两杯威士忌  不加冰
And a couple of whiskeys, neat.
当然  把他甩一边就行
Sure, just throw him over there.
你别误会哈
Don't take this the wrong way,
不过你到底是哪根葱啊
but who the hell are you?
相关空中飞人
A concerned frequent flyer.
给
Here you go.
谢谢  霍莉
Thank you, Holly.
我应该向你道歉
I owe you an apology.
欧文  欧文・马修斯
Owen. Owen Matthews.
你并不想逃跑
You weren't trying to escape.
你怎么发现的
What tipped you off?
是因为我的话
Was it my word
还是因为那个拿注射器扎我的神经病
or the violent psychopath who stabbed me with a syringe?
这是促凝剂
It's a coagulant,
能引起肺栓塞
to trigger a pulmonary embolism.
他想让你的死因
He wanted to make your death
看起来像是深静脉血栓
look like deep vein thrombosis.
自然死因
Natural causes.
他很专业
He's a pro.
你似乎很确定
You seem really sure of that.
换我就会这么做
That's what I would've done,
反正在飞机上会
on a plane anyway.
给  喝了
Here, drink these.
能稀释你的血液
It'll thin out your blood.
我不喝烈酒
I don't drink hard alcohol,
只喝红酒还浅尝而止
only red wine and in moderation.
还有八小时才能降落
We've got eight hours before we land this bird.
有人要让你下不了这架飞机
Someone wants to make sure you don't make it off this plane alive.
所以你不如灌自己喝两杯
So, you might as well have yourself a couple of drinks.
里瑟先生
Yes, Mr. Reese?
欧文・马修斯就是目标受害人
Owen Matthews was the intended victim.
我给你发了张照片
I sent you a picture.
行凶者身上有个纹身
Perp's got a tattoo.
他是枪骑兵   哥伦比亚准军
He's a Lancero, Colombian paramilitary.
有点像我们的巡逻队
Kinda like our rangers,
只是其中有些人收了毒帮的钱
only some of them wind up on the cartel payroll.
从这家伙的手机查不出他老板
Nothing on the guy's cell identifies his boss.
不过我确定你能找出来
But I'm sure you'll find out.
你航班上的两名法警
The two marshals onboard your flight
协助粉碎了一个交易违禁品的网上市场
helped bust an online market in illegal substances,
名叫"黑色集市"
called the Black Market Bazaar.
联调局关闭"黑色集市"展开调查
类似于专供销售毒品的地下网络"易趣"
Think of it as eBay for narcotics on the dark net.
顾客什么都能买到
Customers could get anything
从十几克大麻
from a dime bag of marijuana
到一公斤海洛因
to a kilogram of heroin
二十四小时内送货上门
delivered to their door within 24 hours.
那怎么没人被抓
How does everybody stay out of jail?
"黑色集市"只接受比特币
The Black Market Bazaar only accepts bitcoins,
一种数码货币
a digital cryptocurrency.
网站的匿名"策划大师"
The site was developed by an unknown mastermind
自称"斯芬克斯"
who calls himself the Sphinx.
他目前正被多方通缉
He's still at large and wanted by every agency
包括缉毒署  国际刑警
from the D.E.A. to Interpol.
这位被护送人员一定知道些什么
Transport must know something.
欧文在维护那网站的公司工作
Owen works for the company that hosted the site.
看起来他的工作
It would appear that his job
让他陷入了巨大的危险
has placed him in grave danger.
那两名法警为什么要护送你
Why were those two marshals transporting you?
说来挺有意思
Funny story.
有一天早晨我坐在餐桌前
So, I'm sitting at my kitchen table this morning,
吃早餐
having my breakfast--
吐司  干的  加黄油对心脏不好
toast, dry. Butter's bad for your heart.
就像毒帮的杀手
Almost as bad as a cartel hit man.
那杀手肯定是因为两位"风云"法警
Which is no doubt related to Marshals Crockett and Tubbs
《迈阿密风云》中的两位主角
忽然闯进我的厨房拘留我
infiltrating my kitchen to detain me
当那起黑市案的关键证人
as a critical witness in this black market case.
五个小时后  我就坐在这儿往欧洲飞了
Five hours later, I'm on a flight to Europe
跟着那位裹毯先生
with Mr. Blanket Cover-up
去什么国际法庭作证
to testify in some sort of international court.
关于"黑色集市"你都知道什么
So what do you know about the Black Market Bazaar?
我工作的那家公司维护那网站
The company I work for hosts the site.
但我只是个程序员
But I'm just a programmer.
没奖金  没福利
No bonuses, no benefits.
连个流感疫苗都不给我买单
They don't even pay for my flu shot.
我是无名小卒
I'm a nobody.
训练有素的杀手不会追杀无名小卒
A trained killer doesn't just go after a nobody.
你最好希望他在这架飞机上没有别的朋友
You better hope he doesn't have any friends on this flight.
我告诉你
I'm telling you,
他们找错人了
they got the wrong guy.
不管发生了什么事  都跟我无关
Whatever's going on here, I'm irrelevant.
纽约
你找我
You wanted to see me?
要你走路带点声音不行么
Would it be too much to ask you to snap a twig?
不行  我们有新号码了吗
Not my thing. We get a new number?
没有
No.
但里瑟先生有
But Mr. Reese did.
欧文・马修斯
Owen Matthews--
他现在和他在飞机上
he's on a plane with him now.
跟个号码在飞机上
On a plane with a number?
你安排的吧  哈罗德
You engineer that, Harold?
我保证  我绝对没有
I assure you, I had nothing to do with
害他处于该幽闭环境中  肖女士
his claustrophobic circumstance, Ms. Shaw.
这就引出另一件令人担忧的问题
Which presents us another troubling situation.
怎么了
What's going on?
你需要我做件你不想要我做的事
You need me to do something you don't want me to do.
我需要你去拜访你的前同僚
I need you to visit your former colleagues.
突击队
The Activity?
想要我死的那些人
The people that want me dead.
能问问为什么吗
Mind if I ask why?
恐怕里瑟先生收到的是相关号码
I fear the number that Mr. Reese received is relevant.
飞机上有相关号码
There's a relevant number on the plane?
那另一边会怎么处理
So what's the other side gonna do about it?
这正是我想知道的  肖女士
That's exactly what I want to know, Ms. Shaw.
那我们也许就能知道
Perhaps then we can figure out
为什么机器把约翰安排到那里了
why the machine put John there.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
查出哥伦比亚杀手的雇主了吗
Any progress on ID'ing our Colombian hit man's employer?
恐怕还没有
I'm afraid not.
我希望肖女士能打听到点消息
I had hoped to hear from Ms. Shaw.
我派她去拜访她在情报突击队的前同僚了
I sent her to visit her former colleagues with the I.S.A.
情报突击队  为什么
The I.S.A.? Why?
与欧文・马修斯有关
It was regarding Owen Matthews.
欧文・马修斯是相关号码
Owen Matthews is a relevant number.
你知道多久了
How long have you known?
我什么都不确定
I don't know anything for sure.
我想不明白为什么他们会视
I just couldn't figure out why they would consider
一位中级程序员为相关号码
a mid-level programmer relevant,
所以我派了肖女士去调查
so I sent Ms. Shaw to investigate.
你什么都没告诉我
And you didn't tell me anything?
就像你的机器一样  芬奇
Just like your machine, Finch,
你掌握着所有的信息
you have all the information.
却拒绝分享
You just won't share it.
你为什么会涉及国家安全  欧文
Why are you relevant to national security, Owen?
你能按下服务铃吗
Would you hit your call button?
我很想吃杏仁
I really want some almonds.
你不是无名小卒
You're not a nobody.
你戴着电击皮带
You're wearing a stun belt.
电击皮带有遥控器
And a stun belt has a remote.
给我
Hand it over.
好吧  但杏仁这事儿我可没开玩笑
Okay, but I'm not kidding about those almonds though.
在高空中  我的血糖水平
At high altitudes, my blood sugar
降得很危险了
drops to dangerously low levels--
你为什么会涉及国家安全  欧文
Why are you relevant to national security, Owen?
说来挺有意思
Funny story,
我之前略有点儿淡化了我在黑市的角色
I may have downplayed my whole role in the black market thing before.
我有点不仅仅是程序员
I might be a little more than just a programmer.
说来听听
Tell me about it.
我不喜欢自夸
I don't like to brag.
别别别别
No, no, no, no.
你看上去真暴躁
You seem like an angry guy.
你想谈谈不
Do you wanna talk about that?
我感觉你挺想谈谈
I feel like you wanna talk about that.
行行行行  好吧
Okay, okay, okay, okay, fine.
那个"黑色集市"
The Black Market Bazaar--
是我建的  好吧
I built it, okay?
我是个超棒的网站设计师
I'm a really good designer,
斯芬克斯亲自请我帮忙
And the Sphinx asked for me personally.
他甚至给我买了咖啡  那可是非常难
He even brought me this coffee that is so hard to--
等等
Hold on, hold on.
你见过斯芬克斯本人
You've seen the Sphinx?
是啊  聪明的家伙
Yeah. Smart guy.
名声不太好  但他很有远见
A little misunderstood, but he has a vision.
说来听听
Enlighten me.
他建这个网站
He started the site
是因为对毒品的战争已经输了
because the war on drugs was already lost.
毒帮  街角小弟  地盘争战
Cartels, corner boys, turf wars--
这个网站略掉了中间环节
The site just cuts out the middle man.
为了收钱
For a price.
只是一点手续费
A small transaction fee.
没伤害  没犯规
No harm, no foul.
人们不用再自相残杀了
And people stop killing each other.
就没想过可能是
Ever occur to you that
斯芬克斯想要你命吗
the Sphinx might be the one who wants you dead?
什么  不  我们是好兄弟
What? No, we're pals.
他干嘛要杀我
Why would he want to kill me?
因为你  朋友
Because you, my friend,
也许是唯一能指认他的人
might be the only one who can identify him.
怎么
Yep?
我查出哥伦比亚杀手的雇主了
I've identified your Colombian hit man's employer.
赫南德斯毒帮牵扯"黑色集市"
拉斐尔・赫南德斯
Raphael Hernandez
毒帮的首脑
Cartel kingpin
也是"黑色集市"最大的供货商之一
and one of the Black Market Bazaar's largest suppliers.
我还是查不出拉斐尔和欧文的关系
I still can't find Raphael's connection to Owen.
不用了
No need.
欧文建了整个网站
Owen built the entire site.
他能指认斯芬克斯
He can identify the Sphinx.
也就是说他也能指认
Which means he could also identify
斯芬克斯所有的账号
all the Sphinx's accounts.
如果欧文出庭作证
And if Owen testifies,
他就会威胁到拉斐尔的生意
he could jeopardize Raphael's business as well.
这还是无法解释
None of which explains
为什么他会涉及国家安全
why he's relevant to national security.
让肖操心那个
Let Shaw worry about that.
现在  你我需要查出
Right now, you and I need to find out
那个哥伦比亚杀手有没有同伙
if this Colombian hit man has a partner in crime.
你要去哪儿
Where you going?
要开始颠簸了
The ride's getting pretty bumpy.
安全带指示灯随时会亮
They're gonna turn the seat belt sign on any second.
抱歉  欧文
Sorry, Owen.
你自个儿待一会儿吧
Gotta let you fly solo for a little while.
但我现在是俎上之肉啊
But I'm like a sitting duck.
那就对了
That's the idea.
霍莉
Hello, Holly.
我可以给后座的朋友拿杯酒吗
Could I get a glass of wine for our friend in the back?
他害怕飞行
He's afraid of flying.
当然
Yes, of course.
一切都好吗
Is everything okay?
还行  只是  那俩法警
Fine, it's just-- the marshals,
一个昏迷
one of them's out cold,
另一个还没从厕所出来
the other one hasn't come out of the lav.
你看上去人很好  但是
And you look like a nice enough guy, but--
约翰・维克森
John Wilkinson.
国际国土安全部
Department of International Homeland Security.
国际国土  什么
International home-- what?
我要告诉机长吗
Do I need to update the captain?
不不不  不行
No, no, no, you can't.
现在  机上所有人都有嫌疑
Right now, everyone on this plane is a suspect.
我需要你的帮助
And I need your help.
怎么帮
Help with what?
让大家保持冷静  最好都睡着
Keeping everyone calm, preferably asleep.
熄灯  提供大量脱因咖啡
Lights out, lots of decaf.
好的  可以  还有呢
Okay, I can do that. Anything else?
盯着那嫌犯
Keep an eye on the suspect.
他一站起来  就按这个钮
If he gets up, just hit this button.
能召唤我
It'll summon me.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
机长已经打开安全带指示灯
the captain has turned on the fasten seat belt sign.
请大家回到座位
Everyone should return to their seats
系好安全带
and remain seated with their seat belts fastened.
准备好了吗
就等你了  亲爱的
能控制摇头丸价格的是我们
We control the price of ecstasy,
不是斯芬克斯
not the Sphinx.
看来蜜月结束了
I guess the honeymoon's over.
纽约
环球漫步旅行社
我们刚关门了
We were just closing.
那是当然
Of course you were.
现在谁还会用旅行社啊
Because who the hell uses a travel agency anymore?
我肯定从这儿订过一百次行程了
I must've gotten 100 itineraries from this place,
但我从没想到它真的存在
but I never actually thought it existed.
突击队居然还费心留着店面  有海报
The activity bothers to keep a storefront with posters
有盆栽  真可爱
and dead plants, charming.
恐怕我不知道你在说什么
I'm afraid I don't know what you're talking--
怕就对了
You're right to be afraid.
因为我做了点逆向推理
'Cause I've done a little reverse engineering
从"催化剂"想杀我后就开始了
since catalyst tried to kill me.
列了个清单  反复检查
Made a list, checked it twice.
谁不乖  谁乖
Who's naughty? Who's nice?
而你绝对算不上乖的
And you definitely haven't played nice.
当面见到你很高兴  福斯特
It's nice to meet you in person, Foster.
我本该自我介绍  不过你已经知道我的名字了
I'd introduce myself, but you already know my name.
说吧  我等着
Say it. I'll wait.
-肖  -乖
- Shaw. - Good.
我的搭档呢
And my partner?
科尔
Cole.
你就是那个王八蛋
And you're the facilitating son of a bitch
把我们从柏林召回了纽约
who sent us to New York from Berlin.
你做了预订
You booked the reservations,
但只有我活着回来了
but I'm the only one who made it back alive.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我在说  你非常清楚
What I'm talking about is you're the one person who knows
情报突击队每位成员的动向
where every I.S.A. team is dispatched.
你预订了他们的行程
You book their travel.
你派六个人去追杀我们
You sent a team of six after us.
你预订了接下来的行程
And the next trip you booked
是我们装在棺材里回家
had us coming home in a casket.
只可惜我还活着
Except I'm still here.
所以  催化师先生  你上次
So, Mr. Facilitator, when was the last time
离开桌子是什么时候
you were out from behind the desk?
在我看来
The way I see it,
你欠我的
you owe me a favor,
现在该偿还了
and I'm calling it in.
欧文・马修斯正在飞往罗马的航班上
Owen Matthews is on a flight to Rome right now.
为什么这人涉及国家安全
Why is this man relevant to national security?
你再跟我装傻
You play dumb with me one more time,
我就让你把这条领带吃掉
I'm gonna make you eat this tie.
在你消化掉之前
Except right before you digest it,
我会把它扯出来
I'm gonna pull it back out
然后再重复一遍
and we're gonna do this all over again.
我不知道目标做过什么
I never know what the target's done.
我只知道他们派了名特工
I just know that they sent an operative.
给我号码
Give me a number.
靛蓝6A
Indigo Six Alpha.
空闲中
使用中
听到有骚动  没事吧
Heard a ruckus. Everything okay?
新婚夫妇决定加入高空性爱俱乐部
Newlyweds decided to join the mile-high club.
头等舱就这样  你自己搞定
First-class problem. This one's all you.
我帮你
Let me help you.
给你贴上
Let's get you patched up.
我该通知飞行员的
I should notify the pilot.
-万一那些人醒了怎么办  -不会的
- What if those people wake up? - They won't.
我有安眠药
I borrowed some sleeping pills
从邻座的慈祥老太太那里借的
from the nice older lady sitting next to me.
我得拿着这个
Look, I have to take this.
你能帮我盯着欧文吗
Can you keep an eye on Owen for me?
想要欧文命的并不只有哥伦比亚人
Colombians aren't the only ones who want Owen dead.
有一对前以色列摩萨德特工
A couple of ex-Mossad agents
也不喜欢他
aren't too fond of him either.
他们应该没告诉你原因
I don't suppose they told you why.
关于什么摇头丸的价格
Something about the price of ecstasy,
然后还用叉子扎我
and then they stuck a fork in me.
叉子
A fork?
你知道他们为什么追杀欧文吗
Any idea why they went after Owen?
以色列黑帮控制着欧洲的摇头丸市场
Israeli criminals control Europe's MDMA trade.
可想而知他们不会欢迎
I can't imagine that they would welcome competition
网上毒品市场的竞争
from an online drug market.
我开始怀疑
I'm starting to wonder
这班飞机上有谁不想要欧文命了
who on this plane doesn't want Owen dead.
恐怕肖女士还有更多的坏消息
I'm afraid Ms. Shaw has more bad news.
航班上有名情报突击队的特工
I.S.A. has an operative on the flight:
靛蓝6A
Indigo Six Alpha.
你问过是什么意思了吗
Did you ask your contact what that means?
不必问
Didn't have to.
我是靛蓝5A
I was Indigo Five Alpha.
那人顶替我之前的工作
That guy has my old job,
他是去杀欧文的
and he's there to kill Owen.
告诉我特工的体貌特征
You get the operative's description.
高个  黑暗  西服狠角色
Tall, dark, badass in a suit.
听着耳熟吗
Sound familiar?
不说了
Gotta go.
借过
Excuse me.
请坐
Have a seat.
我需要你们用来控制闹事旅客的束线带
I need the zip ties you keep for unruly passengers,
给他一张毯子  再来杯威士忌
a blanket for this guy, and a shot of whiskey.
给谁
For who?
倒进他的鸭嘴杯里  一指深
Put it in his sippy cup. One finger.
我要去厕所
I have to go to the bathroom.
我们去找妈妈好吗
Why don't we go find your mommy?
欧文
Owen?
机长说我们不能改航线
The captain says we can't divert.
-无处降落  -深呼吸  霍莉
- There's nowhere to land. - Breathe, Holly.
-我做不到  -那就喝酒
- I can't. - Then drink.
我本来可以当老师
I could've been a teacher.
但不  我偏想游历世界
But no, I wanted to see the world,
认识有趣的人
meet interesting people.
这班飞机上有不少有趣的人
There's plenty of interesting people on this plane.
都想杀了对方  可以想象
All trying to kill each other, which I get.
你知道这工作教会了我什么吗
'Cause you know what this job has taught me?
-人真可怕  -我懂你的意思
- That people are horrible. - I know what you mean.
连飞行员都调戏叫我"甜心"  "娃娃脸"
Even the pilots call me "Sweetheart", "Doll face."
而其他的空乘呢
And the other flight attendants?
卡洛斯是个自私的蠢蛋
Carlos is a selfish idiot
业务一塌糊涂
who doesn't know what the hell he's doing.
"帮助别人"这句话没人在乎了吗
What ever happened to people helping other people?
霍利  这话我其实不想说
Holly, I hate to tell you this.
你很擅长这份工作
You're good at your job.
你真贴心  谢谢
That's so nice of you. Thank you for that,
也谢谢你从那个疯子手里救了我
and for saving me from that maniac.
他只是想杀了欧文
He was just trying to kill Owen.
欧文呢
Where is Owen?
他怎么消失了
How did he disappear?
他没有
He didn't.
伙计  我没打算逃跑
Guys. I wasn't trying to escape or anything.
我试过在座位上睡觉
I was actually trying to sleep in my seat.
但我下背部神经压迫太疼了
But I got this terrible pinched nerve in my lower back.
肯定是坐骨神经痛之类的
It must be sciatica or something.
就好像有人在刺我的背
It was like someone was stabbing me in the b--
你应该可以
You can probably relate to--
抱歉  这样快点
Sorry. Sometimes it's just faster.
为什么人人都要他死
Why does everyone want him dead?
他涉及到国家安全
He's relevant to national security.
对啊  就好像你为
Right, just like you work
国际国土安全局工作
for the International Department of Homeland Security.
你究竟是干什么的
What do you really do?
没工作
Nothing.
我辞职了
I quit my job.
你不喜欢你老板吗
Didn't like your boss?
我不喜欢我老板的老板
I didn't like my boss's boss.
带我们去货舱
Just take us to the cargo hold.
就不会再惹麻烦了
And we won't cause any more problems.
晚上好  肖女士
Good evening, Ms. Shaw.
你有没有查到
Have you been able to determine
为什么情报突击队要追杀欧文・马修斯
why the I.S.A. wants Owen Matthew's dead?
正在查
Working on it.
跟位老朋友见面喝杯咖啡
Meeting up with an old friend for coffee.
该死
Damn it.
在翻别人东西吗
Going through other people's stuff?
这可不好
That's not cool.
你找什么呢
What are you looking for?
保险剃须刀  发胶
A safety razor, maybe hair spray.
哥们  你头发挺好
Dude, your hair looks fine.
发间灰白  熟女最爱
That salt and pepper thing's like catnip to soccer moms.
顺其自然吧
Go au naturel.
搞定了情报突击队的特工
Took care of the I.S.A. operative.
还是不确定是不是机器安排的
Still not sure if the machine sent me
也不确定这人值不值得救
or if this guy's worth saving.
你预计会在两小时后着陆
You're scheduled to land in two hours.
肖女士还在努力
Ms. Shaw is still in the process
调查情报突击队追杀欧文的原因
of finding out why I.S.A. wants Owen dead.
情报突击队  哥伦比亚人  以色列人同时追杀
I.S.A., Colombians, Israelis all want the head
一名小小的网站设计师
of a lowly website designer,
而不是
instead of a...
策划大师
mastermind.
看  我就讨厌你这么看着我
See, I hate it when you look at me like that.
太不礼貌了
It's not polite.
你不只建了网站
You didn't just build the site.
你知道工作原理
You know how it works,
知道钱在哪里
where the money's at.
好吧  我又不是傻瓜
Okay, look, I'm not a moron, all right?
我拿了一点钱  转移了几个账户
I socked away a few funds, diverted some accounts.
还有别的事要告诉我吗  欧文
Something else you wanna tell me, Owen?
好好  行行
Okay, okay, fine, fine.
别电击我了  哥们
Don't tase me, bro.
我不只建了网站
I didn't just build the site.
我就是那人
I'm the guy.
你就是斯芬克斯
You're the Sphinx.
我在卧室里创造了一个商业模型
I created a business model from my bedroom
那是网络交易的革命
that revolutionized an international market
可以把贩毒业的暴力事件减半
and cut violence in the drug trade by half.
不用谢
You're welcome.
是啊  大家都排队等着感谢你呢
Yeah, people are just lining up to thank you.
没事  我有计划了
It's okay. I have a plan.
好吧  我有价值一亿美元的比特币
Okay, I have 100 million bucks in bitcoins.
只要你保我安全下飞机  避开国际刑警
You get me off this plane and past Interpol in one piece,
我就跟你平分
I'll split it with you.
很划算  是吧
Good deal, right?
你真把自己当策划大师
You think you're a mastermind.
那是媒体起的名字  不是我
That's the media's word, not mine.
你们这些搞电脑的
You computer guys,
尽造一些自己控制不了的东西
you build something you can't control.
一旦事与愿违  又不肯承担责任
And when it backfires, you won't accept responsibility.
这是在说什么啊
What are we talking about here?
你真的有改善任何东西吗
Have you really made anything better?
你觉得这是制止暴力吗
Does it look like you've stopped the violence?
好吧  这还是在说我么
Okay, are we still talking about me?
你好像是在生某人的气
'Cause it seems like you're mad at somebody else.
我以为你搞定那肌肉男了
I thought you got rid of that walking steroid.
看来没有
Guess not.
头晕
Dizzy?
舌头发痒
Tongue a little itchy?
肖
Shaw.
你曾经教过我  身为特工必须
You once taught me that an operative should always
在喝东西前先沾唇  试毒
wet their lips and wait for symptoms before drinking anything.
[神经抑制剂]莨菪碱
Scopolamine.
马上就会心跳过速
Tachycardia will be setting in shortly.
疲倦  记忆缺失
Fatigue, amnesia--
我知道药效
I know what the drug does.
你还有意识  但已经变得温顺了
You're conscious, but you've been rendered completely docile.
我在出任务
I'm on a job right now.
之前是
You were.
用手提电脑的那个眼镜男  对吧
Guy with the glasses on the laptop, right?
你今晚要杀的号码就是他吧
That was the number you were supposed to kill tonight?
我把你教得很好
I trained you well.
好过头了
Too well.
我一直很喜欢你  赫什
I always liked you, Hersh.
即便在你杀我之后
Even after you killed me.
你安排了一名情报突击队特工上飞机杀这人
You put an I.S.A. operative on a flight to kill this guy.
为什么
Why?
他在地下网络建了最大的毒品交易市场
He built the biggest narcotics marketplace on the dark net--
交易金额数十亿美元
billion dollars in sales.
阻止不了毒品交易  总可以课税
You can't stop the drug trade, but you can tax it.
课税  什么时候
Tax it? Since when?
我们一年前盯上了斯芬克斯
We were on to the Sphinx a year ago.
但为给我们的活动提供资金
But when it comes to funding our operation,
黑色预算永远不够
the black budget only goes so far.
所以我们从总收入里拿了三成
So we took 30% off the top.
那为何现在要除掉他
So why take him out now?
没人过问我们如何保障国家安全
Nobody asks how we keep the country safe.
但那孩子一公开  他们就会开始过问
But they'll start if that kid goes public.
危及国家安全
National security risk.
那架飞机是绝好的机会
And that flight is a perfect window of opportunity.
我看你们在那飞机上可遇着竞争对手了
I think you might have some competition on the plane.
肖  你的新老板们
Shaw, your new employers...
他们对你好吗
are they treating you okay?
他们还没想杀我
They haven't tried to kill me yet.
我今晚本可以杀了你  赫什  但我没有
I could've killed you tonight, Hersh, and I didn't.
真遗憾你不会记得
Too bad you won't remember any of this.
别打脸
Not the face.
让开
Fore.
好球
Nice shot.
里瑟先生  看来情报突击队
Mr. Reese, it seems that the I.S.A.
与"黑色集市"达成了
took a mutually beneficial financial interest
互惠互利的经济利益
in the Black Market Bazaar,
因此他们不能让此事曝光
which they could ill afford to have come out.
这还是不能解释
It still doesn't explain
为什么机器把我安排到这飞机上
why the machine put me on this plane.
我设计这机器
I didn't program the machine
不是为了监测国家丑闻  里瑟先生
to detect national embarrassments, Mr. Reese.
我设计它来预防国家灾难
I designed it to prevent a national tragedy.
你是说他们有所遗漏
You're saying they missed something?
他们不是唯一想要欧文命的
They aren't the only ones who want Owen dead.
拉斐尔・赫南德斯曾经炸掉
Raphael Hernandez once blew up
[哥伦比亚]麦德林一家酒店的整层楼
an entire floor of a hotel in Medellin
以阻止证人出庭作证
to prevent a witness from testifying.
我已经解决了拉斐尔的杀手
I already took out Raphael's hit man.
我进入了他的邮箱
I've accessed his email.
拉斐尔命令他的手下除掉欧文  不择手段
Raphael has ordered his team to take out Owen by any means necessary,
不惜击落整架飞机
even if it means taking down the plane.
邮件里显示了多少名杀手
How many hit squad members were on that email?
两位  哥伦比亚准军
Two--Colombian paramilitary.
另有一名枪骑兵登机了
There's another Lancero onboard.
但我查过旅客名单  查过了每名乘客
But I checked the manifest, every passenger.
不是乘客  芬奇
He's not a passenger, Finch.
晚上好  机长
Good evening, Captain.
自动飞行
追踪航班
紧急威胁
原定飞行路线
罗马
他失血过多
He's lost a lot of blood.
一小时内不能将他送到医院  他就没命了
If we don't get him to the hospital in the next hour, he's a goner.
我听到了声音
I heard something,
看到卡洛斯进了驾驶舱
Saw Carlos enter the cockpit.
锁住了  对讲机没响应
It's locked. No response from the intercom.
飞机在倾斜
The plane's banking.
我们在下坠
We're losing altitude.
我联系不上塔台
And I can't contact the tower.
我就知道那家伙不对劲
I knew there was something off about that guy.
因为他不是空乘
It's because he's not a flight attendant.
他是职业刺客  空降兵
He's a professional assassin, paratrooper.
他在带我们下坠
He's taking us down.
你得把我弄进去  马上
I need you to get me in there, now.
他重设了密码
He's overridden the code.
情况很危险  芬奇  你能帮我们吗
The situation's critical, Finch. Can you help us?
我正在试着进入飞行管理系统
I'm trying to get into the flight management system
通过飞机的卫星链路
through the plane's satellite link.
-欧文在哪儿  -躲在货舱
- Where is Owen? - Stashed in the cargo hold.
我要借用下这个
I'm gonna need to borrow this.
里瑟先生  我进入了飞行管理系统
Mr. Reese, I've gotten into the F.M.S.
看来他关闭了自动驾驶
It appears that he's disabled the autopilot.
我无法取消手动操作模式
I can't seem to override the manual operator.
你之前开过这种尺寸的飞机吗
You ever flown a plane this size before?
果断没有  只开过螺旋桨飞机
Heavens no, props only.
这可是架民航大型喷气式客机
This is a commercial jumbo jet.
得有人手动降落
Somebody's gonna have to stick the landing.
我开免提了
I'm putting you on speaker.
打扰下  给我点水好吗
Excuse me. Can I have some water, please?
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
飞机受气流影响有些颠簸
we're experiencing a bit of turbulence.
机长请大家在位置上坐好
The captain asks that everyone remain seated at this time.
收起小桌板
Make sure your tray tables are up
系好安全带
and all seat belts are fastened.
我的上帝  发生了什么
Oh, my God. What's happening?
里瑟先生  现在谁在开飞机
Mr. Reese, who's flying the plane?
需要帮下忙  芬奇
Need a little help, Finch.
天啊
Oh, dear.
芬奇  我们在下坠
Finch, we're going down.
抱紧了  里瑟先生
Hold on tight, Mr. Reese.
操纵杆方向舵  操纵杆方向舵
Stick and rudder, stick and rudder.
警告
交替飞行控制
启动
微步修正  机翼水平
Small corrections. Wings level.
风速  姿态
Airspeed and attitude.
带我们回家  芬奇
Take us home, Finch.
保持水平  保持水平
Keep it level, keep it level.
近了  要降落了
I'm coming in too hot. I'm gonna be long.
会有些颠簸
There might be a bounce.
听到了吗  芬奇
You hear that, Finch?
为你的
That's for you.
已经安全降落了
Yeah, you just stuck this bird.
谢谢你  里瑟先生
Thank you, Mr. Reese.
欧文怎么样
How about Owen?
唯一的相关号码是飞机上的130名乘客
The only relevant number on this plane is 130 people.
[意]谢谢
Grazie.
[意]再见
Arrivederci.
话说你到底干什么工作
So what is it you really do again?
我帮助别人
I help people.
要帮我来一杯吗
You wanna help me get a drink?
能给找个让我喘得了气的箱子吗
Man, do you think you could've stuffed me into a case that breathed?
下次  直接给我头上套个垃圾袋
Next time, just throw a garbage bag over my head
再往棺材里一扔算了
and stick me in a casket.
给  去这个地址
Here. Go to this address.
等着  直到一个叫哈罗德的人联系你
Stay there until you hear from a man named Harold.
哈罗德  电话那头的那个人吗
Harold? The guy on the phone?
你出局了
You're out of business.
低调点
Stay off the grid.
别联系之前认识的任何人
Do not reach out to anyone you once knew.
那我想送你点东西
What if I wanna send you something,
作为报答呢
repay you for all you've done?
我不为钱  欧文
I'm not in it for the money, Owen.
你说的好像这是你的工作
You almost say that like it's your job,
那也太疯狂了
which would be insane.
不管你是为什么  好样的
Whatever you're in it for, good on you, man.
谢谢你救我一命
I appreciate you saving my neck.
-谢谢你来见我  -谢谢你请我喝酒
- Thanks for meeting me. - Thanks for the drink.
希望你回航时遇到好点的机组
I hope you get a better crew to work with on your return flight.
如果你回城的话  给我电话
Give me a call if you're ever back in the city.
-再见  -再见
- Ciao. - Ciao.
她似乎不错
She seems nice.
你跟踪我吗  哈罗德
You track me down, Harold?
只是飞过来帮欧文适应
Just flew in to get Owen situated
新身份和新目标
with a new identity and destination.
就这样
Is that it?
[意]谢谢
Grazie.
里瑟先生  我理解你
Mr. Reese, I understand your frustration
对机器的混沌状况深感挫败
with the opacity of the machine.
但我选择将它设计成这样是有原因的
But there's a reason I chose to make it that way.
机器只给我们号码
The machine only gives us numbers,
因为我一直相信
because I would always rather that
要有人类才能决定
a human element remain in determining
他人性命攸关的事
something so critical as someone's fate.
我们有自由意志
We have free will.
相伴的是重大的责任
And with that comes great responsibility
有时是重大的损失
and sometimes great loss.
我同样深切怀念她
I miss her dearly too.
你什么时候走
When are you leaving?
很快
Soon.
我想去看看这个展览
I thought I would go see this exhibit
在乔治・德・基里科纪念博物馆
at the Giorgio De Chirico House-Museum...
此人为形而上学画派创始人之一
格蕾丝很喜欢这位艺术家
an artist that Grace was very fond of.
欢迎你来陪我
You're welcome to join me.
我不确定我可以  芬奇
I'm not sure I can, Finch.
既然来了意大利  我想订做套新西装
While I'm in Italy, I thought I'd get fitted for a new suit.
当然了
Of course.
我们应该打电话给我在帕勒斯的订制工作室
We should call my atelier in the Via Palestro.
让詹尼安排在午餐后
See if Gianni could fit you in after lunch.
他是最好的
He's the best.
我想搭你的飞机  跟你一起回去
I thought maybe I could hitch a ride back with you.
我可不想再乘民航客机了
I'm not quite ready to fly commercial yet, so--
但我得回去工作啊
but I need to get back to work.
肯定的  里瑟先生
Certainly, Mr. Reese.
我认识飞行员
I know the pilot.
我们可以把航班延期
I think we could delay that flight.